（我愛羅）来たな…。
Here they come...
（カブト）無の動きが止まった。
Mu is not moving.
チャクラも姿もない。
There's no sign of him
or his chakra.
無人と恐れられた　二代目土影が
感知されたようだね。
Seems the Second Tsuchikage
has been detected.
Even though he was known
as the "Null Man."
そろそろ　戦場が育ってくる…。
It will soon be ripe for war.
ここからが本番…。
The real fight is just beginning.
あのクラスの忍ならば→
With that class of shinobi,
I anticipate bigger results
思考や感情は殺さぬほうが
大きな戦果が期待できるか…。
by not killing off their
thoughts and emotions.
口寄せのあとは
自由にやらせてみるか…。
I'll let him do as he pleases
after the Summoning Jutsu.
it's infinite, it's infinite, it's infinite, rock assault
eien desu eien desu eien desu totsugeki rock
I was asleep all this time, I kept quiet all this time
zutto nemutteta zutto damatteta
hey, it's calling us, hey, let's go
ooi yonde iru ooi itte mi yo
I can see something far away
tooku ni nanika ga mieru
something more important now than studying
benkyou yori mo ima taisetsu na mono
hey, it's calling us, hey, let's go
ooi yonde iru ooi itte mi yo
I think we can find it
mitsukarisou nanda
it's infinite, it's infinite, it's infinite, rock assault
eien desu eien desu eien desu totsugeki rock
see, you can overtake the future
mirai wa hora oinuite
this ship can really fly through the sky
hontou wa sora toberu fune
The Brilliant Military Advisor of the Hidden Leaf
（カブト）二代目土影　三代目雷影。
The Second Tsuchikage...
The Third Raikage...
二代目水影　四代目風影。
The Second Mizukage...
The Fourth Kazekage...
火影がいないのが残念だが…。
Too bad we don't have
a Hokage.
歴代四影が揃うのだからな…。
Still, four Kage from history
are here.
思う存分　子孫たちと
殺し合うがいい。
I'll just let the Kage and
their progeny kill each other off.
ん？　何だ　ここは？
Where am I?
これはこれは
かつての敵どうしが揃って…。
My, my... What a gathering
of former enemies!
いや…　こいつは知らないな。
Well, well. I don't know this guy.
これは　二代目火影の
卑劣な術だ。
This is a foul jutsu of
the Second Hokage.
死者を黄泉から呼んで縛る…。
The dead are summoned back from
the afterlife and then bound.
お前らを　ここへ
無理やり口寄せさせられた。
You were summoned here by force.
死者を！？　どういうことだ？
The dead?! What do you mean?
忘れたか？
お前を殺したのは　俺だ。
Have you forgotten?
I killed you myself.
お前は　とっくに死んでたのさ
二代目水影。
You died ages ago,
Second Mizukage.
あぁ…　あのときか…
って　おい！
Oh... back then... Hey wait!
あのとき　お前も
一緒に死んだだろうが！
You also died that day!
In fact, I killed you.
いや　殺してやったろ。
だったか…。
Was that so?
まぁ　そんなことはいい。
Well, no matter.
話を進めるぞ。　でだ…。
Let me continue...
Where was I?
俺たちを復活させた術者…。
Where is the Second Hokage?
二代目火影は　どこだ？
He's the jutsu user
who resurrected us?
辺りに感じるのは　この数キロ先…。
I detect someone
several kilometers ahead.
この新顔と同じ　チャクラを感じる。
One with the same chakra
as this new face...
それも　大軍とともに。
along with a huge army.
貴様は　たしか…。
No doubt you are...
俺は　四代目風影だ…。
I am the Fourth Kazekage.
あんたたちの武勇伝は
先代から聞いている。
My predecessors have told me
about your exploits.
少なくとも　砂は四代目…。
So this means the Sand
has continued
いや　五代目までは
続いたってことか。
through to the fourth,
no, the fifth generation.
未来の世界にいるってのは
どうも　ヘンテコな気分だぜ。
It feels strange
being in the future.
言っとくが
ここは　未来ではない。
Listen, this is not the future.
俺たちが　過去の存在なのだ。
We're just beings from the past.
話の腰を折るな　殺すぞ！
And don't interrupt me,
or I'll kill you.
…てか　殺されたんだよ！
But I was killed.
And I killed you!
てか　殺してやったけどな！
だから　そうじゃなくて→
I was just telling you the story
俺たちを復活させた
二代目火影の話をだな。
of the Second Hokage
who resurrected us...
俺たちの世代で
二代目火影は　とっくに死んでた。
The Second Hokage was
long dead by my time.
しかし　この術…
穢土転生を使えた忍がいた…。
But there was a shinobi capable
of using the Reanimation Jutsu.
大蛇丸というやつだ。
A shinobi named Orochimaru.
（我愛羅）４人…　うち１人は…。
Four... and among them...
父様か…。
is Father.
That's all.
（シカマル）本部から連絡だ。
It's a message from Headquarters.
奇襲部隊が
敵の奇襲部隊と接触。
Our Commando Unit has skirmished
with the enemy's Commando Unit.
敵は　予想どおりだが→
Our predictions about
the enemy were correct.
穢土転生という術で→
But they are raising the dead
with a jutsu
死者をよみがえらせて
戦場に送り込んできた。
known as the Reanimation Jutsu and
sending them onto the battlefield.
（テマリ）この戦場にも→
Who knows what kind of shinobi
we'll see on the battlefield.
どんなやつが
送り込まれてくるかわからない。
みんな　覚悟してくれ。
So everyone, be prepared.
（シカマル）合図だ。
That's the signal.
敵は　近いぞ。
The enemy is near.
本部からは　敵を感知したという
連絡は　なかったのに→
But there's no word
from Headquarters
that they detected the enemy.
どういうことだ？
What's going on?
本部でも感知できねえような
やつがいたんだろ。
It probably means there are guys
that even Headquarters
cannot sense.
まあ　強えやつしか→
After all, the enemy will only
revive the strong ones.
生き返らせねえだろうからよ
そりゃあ…。
（チョウジ）死者と戦うなんて…。
We have to fight dead people?
ど　どうしよう…。
僕　怖くなってきた。
What do I do?
I'm getting scared.
おい　チョウジ　ここまできて
今更　泣き言はなしだぜ。
Hey Choji, now that you're here
it's too late to whine.
う　うん…。
U-Uh-huh...
我愛羅隊長率いる
第四部隊より連絡。
We just received word from
Captain Gaara's Fourth Company.
敵　４名を発見。
Four of the enemies have
been spotted.
敵は　二代目水影
二代目土影　四代目風影→
They are the Second Mizukage,
the Second Tsuchikage,
the Fourth Kazekage and...
それから…。
（エー）で　あと１人は？
And who's the other?!
三代目雷影様です…。
The Third Raikage.
何！？　親父まで！？
What?!
My old man too?!
ええい　暁め！
Damn the Akatsuki!
（綱手）こちらの感知反応と
数が合わないが→
The numbers don't match up with
our own sensory readings.
情報は　たしかなのか！
Are you sure this data is accurate?
（オオノキ）綱手姫よ…。
Princess Tsunade...
現れたのは　二代目土影。
It's the Second Tsuchikage
that has appeared.
どおりでじゃぜ。
Huh?!
It's no wonder we
could sense three,
突然　感知反応が
３つ出たうえに→
１人分　こっちでは
感知できとらん。
but couldn't detect one.
こっちで感知できなかったのは
間違いなく無様の仕業じゃぜ…。
The reason sensory detection
was futile is the doing of Lord Mu.
《青：本部の感知システム術ですら
感知できないやつがいるのか…。
There's someone who
can evade detection
from even the Headquarters'
Sensory Radar Jutsu?!
なんてやつだ！》
What is he?
青様！
あの白いバケモノの数が多すぎて→
Captain Ao!
There are far too many
of those white monsters.
特定の人物を感知しきるのは
私では　無理です。
It's impossible for me to detect
the ones with
special characteristics.
そろそろ　ダルイ第一部隊と
敵数千が接触します！
Darui's First Company
will soon encounter
several thousand enemy troops!
白いやつと　穢土転生組との
分別感知をお願いします！
Please distinguish the white ones
from those under
the Reanimation Jutsu!
わかった。
お前は　拡大感知を担当しろ！
All right!
You take charge of
the broad-range scan!
やばいぞ！
ダルイ第一部隊相手に→
Huh?!
This is not good!
穢土転生組が　多すぎる！
Darui's First Company will
be facing too many
who are under
the Reanimation Jutsu!
しかも　どいつもこいつも
名の通ったやつばかりだ！
Furthermore,
they're all powerful shinobi!
♪～
（ダルイ）くるぜ…　戦闘態勢の合図だ。
They're coming.
Give the signal to get
into position for battle.
ハッ！
Right.
（テンテン）すごい数なんだけど…。
There are so many...
（ヒアシ）どうやら　数だけではない。
It's not just their numbers.
本部からの連絡どおり
白眼で手練どもを確認できる。
Headquarters was right.
I can distinguish the adept ones
with my Byakugan.
ヒアシ様　１０時の方向を。
Lord Hiashi!
Look towards 10 o'clock.
あ　あれは…。
Th-That's...
まさか　そんな…。
N-No way. That can't be...
どうした？
あいつらが何だってんだ？
What's wrong?
What about them?
あの方がたは…
金角様と銀角様だ。
That's...
They're... Lords Kinkaku and Ginkaku...
何だ　この２人は！？
九尾のチャクラを帯びているぞ。
What?! These two are bathed
in the Nine Tails' chakra!
すごいチャクラだ。
え～い　間違いない。
Incredible chakra!
There's no doubt!
雲の金銀兄弟だ。
They are the Gold and Silver
Brothers of the Hidden Cloud.
何？
What?
《ダンまでいるのか…》
Even Dan is among them?
え～い…。
第四部隊には　親父
第一部隊には　金角　銀角。
The Fourth Company is
facing my old man.
And the First Company is looking
at Kinkaku and Ginkaku.
どちらにしても　こうなっては
わしが出るしかない。
Now that it's come to this,
I have no choice
but to go out there myself.
（シカク）待ってください。
Please wait...
雷影様は　忍連合軍総大将。
Lord Raikage...
You are the Supreme Commander
of the Allied Shinobi Forces!
総大将は
戦闘の最終段階まで無事でいて→
The Supreme Commander must
remain safe in order to give orders
指揮をとり続けなければならない。
to the troops until
the final stages of the war.
それが部下に対する責任です。
That is your duty towards
your charges.
しかし　ダルイ第一部隊に
強敵が集中しすぎているぞ。
But an enemy force
of enormous strength
is converging
on Darui's First Company!
戦闘状況は　生き物と同じ
刻一刻と変化してる。
The tide of battle is
like a living thing.
It changes second by second.
それを見極めるために
俺がここにいる。
To discern those changes
is why I am here!
地図を。
Bring me the map!
まずは　各部隊の確認から
行いましょう。
First, let us verify
every company's status.
最も先行しているのが
カンクロウ率いる奇襲部隊です。
At the forefront is
Kankuro's Commando Unit.
KANKURO COMMANDO UNIT
REANIMATED SASORI DEIDARA UNIT
穢土転生組の奇襲部隊と
接触した模様ですが→
KANKURO COMMANDO UNIT
REANIMATED SASORI DEIDARA UNIT
It seems they have
skirmished with
a Commando Unit of
reanimated shinobi.
敵を撃破　現在は　更に
暁のアジトに向かって進行中です。
However, they defeated the enemy!
Presently, they are moving forward
towards the Akatsuki hideout.
戦闘部隊として
最も先行しているのは→
Among the combat battalions,
Kakashi's Third Company
is leading the charge.
カカシ第三部隊です。
KAKASHI THIRD COMPANY
現在　戦闘中ですが　ここはすでに
有利に推移しています。
SEVEN NINJA SWORDSMEN
They are in the midst of battle now,
but they have taken
the advantage.
うむ。
現状の主戦場とも言えるのは→
Right now, the main battle
is being waged here
黄ツチ第二部隊が戦う　この場所。
by Kitsuchi's Second Company.
KITSUCHI SECOND COMPANY
WHITE ZETSU UNIT
そして　あらゆる戦場を
バックアップするために→
And Mifune's Fifth Company is standing by
MIFUNE FIFTH COMPANY
ミフネ第五部隊が
縦に長くスタンバっています。
to assist in any battle.
さて　ここからです。
Now then, it begins right here.
海よりやってきた敵部隊。
The enemy unit that came by sea.
それに対するのは　ダルイ第一部隊。
Darui's First Company
will take them on.
COASTLINE WHITE ZETSU UNIT
DARUI FIRST COMPANY
ここをＡ戦場としましょう。
Let's call this Battlefield A.
更に　突如現れた→
And facing the previous Kage
who suddenly appeared...
REANIMATED FOUR KAGE
歴代影たちと対するのは→
我愛羅第四部隊となります。
GAARA FOURTH COMPANY
is Gaara's Fourth Company.
ここをＢ戦場としましょう。
We'll call this Battlefield B.
ふむ　こうして見ると→
戦力は　まんべんなく
行き渡っているようだな。
When you look at it like this,
we seem to be evenly
matched in strength.
それがまずいんです。
うん？
It's unwise to think that.
兵力を集中して
有利に立つのが戦術の鉄則。
The ironclad rule of warfare is
to take the advantage
by mobilizing troops!
二方向からの敵。
ENEMY                         ENEMY
The enemy advances
from two directions.
これに対しては
一方に　兵力を集中して→
You counter that by attacking from
one direction with full force.
徹底的に叩く。
うむ…。
ここでは　戦場ＡとＢの　２か所が
それです。
We are dealing with
two battlefields here.
A and B...
この場合　まずは　Ａを叩く。
First, we must deal with A.
ダルイ第一部隊側に　兵力を集中する。
We will concentrate our troops
with Darui's First Company.
まず　ミフネ第五部隊を帯状のまま→
So, we will deploy
Mifune's Fifth Company
増援部隊として　向かわせつつ
最後尾を　合流させる。
in belt formation as support to
reinforce the ranks from the rear.
そして
黄ツチ第二部隊を　横に展開して→
Then we will move Kitsuchi's
Second Company to the side
海から　敵を挟むように囲む。
and box the enemy in
from the sea.
それによって
黄ツチ第二部隊が　手薄になるが→
Kitsuchi's Second Company
may be stretched thin.
帯状に　長く展開している
第五部隊が　壁になる。
But, the Fifth Company's deployment
in belt formation
will serve as a barrier.
更に　我愛羅第四部隊は→
Meanwhile, Gaara's Fourth Company
will break up and
敵を中心に
逆くの字に折れながら→
make a slow retreat to
the opposite side of the village
敵を誘い込むように
ゆっくりと後退する。
as if to lure the enemy.
そのまま　逆くの字の半分は→
From there, half of the company
will join up
ダルイ第一部隊へ
更に　増援部隊として合流させる。
with Darui's First Company
as reinforcements.
そして
戦場Ａで　敵を殲滅したのち→
And after the enemy is crushed
in Battlefield A,
ダルイ第一部隊と　我愛羅分隊連合で
戦場Ｂへ向かい→
Darui's First Company and
Gaara's squads will turn back
towards Battlefield B...
我愛羅第四部隊が
引きつけておいた　戦場Ｂの敵を→
and the enemy that Gaara's
Fourth Company had kept occupied
後方から　一気に叩く！
will be crushed from the rear
all at once.
う～む…。
なぜ　戦場Ａからだ？
Why start with Battlefield A?
それに
我愛羅第四部隊を　半分にすれば→
If you split
Gaara's Fourth Company into two,
戦場Ｂの敵が　それを機に
一気に攻め込んでくる場合もある。
won't the enemy seize that
opportunity to attack?
たかが　４人と侮るなよ！
Don't underestimate those four.
相手は　歴代の影たちなのだ！
They are former Kage!
まず　戦場Ａには→
With Battlefield A, Companies Two
and Five are in close proximity
第二　第五部隊が近く
早く　行動できます。
to Battlefield A and
can move quickly.
それに
戦闘を経て　敵を知っている→
Also, Kitsuchi's Second Company
has engaged the white ones before
黄ツチ第二部隊が　白いやつを
後方から攻めることができ→
and is familiar with them.
Attacking the white clones
from the rear
高い効果が　期待できます。
will ensure a high rate of success.
そして…　戦場Ｂの敵。
As for the enemy in Battlefield B...
歴代四影は　攻め込み切れない。
The former Kage cannot
launch an attack.
急に　こちらの隊が
半分になれば→
If the troops suddenly
break off into two,
敵は　何かあるとみて
うかつに　深追いできない。
the enemy will assume we're up
to something and will not charge.
ふむ…　戦争を経験している
歴代影だからこそ→
The war-savvy former Kage will
not be so foolish as to attack...
うかつに
攻めてこないということか…。
なるほどじゃぜ。
I see.
仮に　攻め込んできたとしても→
And even if they were to attack,
我愛羅第四部隊は
戦闘遠距離部隊…。
Gaara's Fourth Company is
a long-range battle unit.
遠距離攻撃を得意とし→
They specialize in fighting from
a distance, which means
近距離戦闘に持ち込むまでは
時間をかけられる。
it would take longer to engage them
in a short-distance battle.
つまり　時間稼ぎを
しやすい部隊といえます。
In other words, it is a company
that could buy us time.
どうします？　総大将…。
What will you do,
Supreme Commander?
木ノ葉を　なかなか
落とせなかったわけだ…。
No wonder we could not
take down the Leaf.
いい忍がいるな　綱手。
You are blessed with
fine shinobi, Tsunade.
褒めんのは
戦争が終わってからにしな。
Save the compliments
for after the war.
で…　どうするんだ？
So? What will you do?
よし…　やってみろ！
All right! Let's do it!
いのいち　聞いていたな！
Inoichi,
you've been listening, right?
（いのいち）もう　連絡した！
それと　奇襲部隊の件は
ミフネ部隊に　連絡済みだ。
I'm already on it. Also...
We've already sent word to Mifune
about the Commando Unit.
向かってる。
They are on their way.
シズネには　隊を　均等に分配して
医療に当たらせている。
And Shizune is allocating
her people evenly
to provide medical attention.
大軍に　穢土転生の部隊…。
A unit resurrected from
the Reanimation Jutsu
いよいよ　戦争なのね…。
is part of the army.
War is finally beginning.
（チョウザ）本部じゃ
シカクが作戦を考えてる。
Shikaku is thinking about
strategy at Headquarters.
あいつの頭は　めちゃくちゃ
回転がいいからな。
That guy is
an amazingly clear thinker.
俺なんかが思いつかないような
すげえ作戦を→
He comes up with brilliant tactics
that I could never dream up.
すぐ思いつくのさ。
そいつを　すかさず
いのいちのやつが→
Oh...
And Inoichi will pass that on
to us without fail.
俺たちに　連絡してくれる。
俺は　あいつらを信じて
ここで戦う！
I have faith in them and
we will battle right here.
そうだ！　仲間を信じて！
Yes! Have faith in our comrades.
♪～
（キバ）でや～っ！
そうですよね。
You're right.
仲間のためにも
ここは　私たちが食い止めなきゃ。
We have to hold back the enemy,
for our comrades' sake.
ありがとう　チョウザさん。
Thank you, Choza.
うむ！
全部隊に連絡完了！
All companies have been notified!
よ～し。
All right, it's been a while since
Ino-Shika-Cho went into action!
久しぶりに
猪鹿蝶といきますか！
ひとついいか？
木ノ葉の奈良の者。
I have one question,
Nara from the Hidden Leaf.
何でしょう？
お前の作戦を完璧にするには→
What is it?
In order for your strategy
to be foolproof,
少々　手を
加えねばならんことがある。
you must add in one thing.
と　いいますと？
Which is?
二代目土影は　ただの忍ではない。
The Second Tsuchikage is
no ordinary shinobi.
両天秤のジジイでなければ
止められん。
The only one who can stop him
is the old Fence-Sitter.
先ほどから　たびたび
話題にされていた忍ですね。
His name has come up often
in our discussions.
どんな忍なんです？
What kind of shinobi is he?
チャクラ感知できない時点で→
From the time I heard that
his chakra could not be detected,
すでに　やっかいだとは
思っているのですが。
I knew he would be a problem.
血継限界の更に上
血継淘汰と呼ばれる忍だ。
He is known as
a Kekkei Touta shinobi...
which is a considerably higher
level than the Kekkei Genkai.
血継淘汰！？
Kekkei Touta?!
それは　三代目土影
あなただけのこととばかり…。
I thought you, Third Tsuchikage,
were the only one...
まさか　二代目まで。
The Second Tsuchikage too?
風　土　火の性質　３つを
一度に合わせることのできる→
The ability to activate
the three chakra natures
of wind, earth and fire,
all at once.
塵遁を　わしに教えてくれた
かつての師じゃぜ。
He was my teacher
who taught me the Particle Style.
この歳で　師匠と
戦うことになるとはな。
To have to battle my master
at this age...
長生きはするもんじゃぜ。
It does not pay
to live a long life.
行ってくれるか？
うむ…。
Will you go?
しかたあるまい。
Yes.
What choice do I have?
奈良の者よ。
はい。
Nara...
わしが行くのは　塵遁の無様が
そこにいるからだけではない。
Yes?
I'm not going just because Lord Mu
of the Particle Style is there.
先ほどの作戦は　見事。
Your tactical plan is brilliant.
そして　第四部隊と対峙する
歴代影たちは→
And while all the resurrected Kage
戦争を知ってるがゆえに
うかつな行動には出ん。
who stand before
the Fourth Company know war,
they will not make
unnecessary moves.
その戦場心理も
およそ　そのとおりじゃろう。
You are probably right in
your battle assessment.
じゃがな　逆もまた　しかりじゃぜ。
But the opposite is also possible.
戦闘連隊を
一つにまとめた我愛羅。
The one who united
the Allied Forces is Gaara.
それは　若さゆえの情熱が
大きな要因だが→
His youthful passion was
the primary catalyst.
戦場では　それが
逆効果になることも→
And you are saying
あるということか。
this can have the opposite effect
on the battlefield?
ご高察　感謝いたします。
I appreciate your insight.
うむ。　さて　ひとっ飛びして→
Well then, I guess it's time
to leap into the war
戦争を知らんガキどもに→
戦い方ってもんを
教えてやるかのう。
and show these young brats
what fighting is all about.
特に　あの生意気な若造にな。
Especially that brazen young kid.
二代目火影の死者を操る術。
A jutsu that controls
the Second Hokage's corpse...
術者は
二代目火影ではないようだが→
The user doesn't seem to be
the Second Hokage,
この穢土転生とやら→
but this Reanimation Jutsu...
体がいうことを
きかなくなるときがあるな。
There are times when your body
won't do what you want it to.
一定の行動を制限される。
Movement is restricted.
どうやら　そうみてえだな。
Seems that way.
さっき　お前を殺そうと思ったが
体がいうことをきかねえ。
I thought about
killing you earlier,
but my body wouldn't let me.
あんたたちとも
戦ってみたかったがな。
I would have enjoyed
battling you all.
残念　残念。
Such a shame, such a shame...
《我愛羅か…》
Gaara, eh...
you and I held hands tightly and a light was born
kimi to boku nigirishimeta futatsu no te no naka de
let's release it now
umareta hikari ima hanatou
the town, tinged amber by the sunset
kohaku iro no yuuyake ni somerareta
projects a sad light and shadow
machi wa kanashii hikari to kage utsushite ita
I've encountered and gotten tangled
ikutsu mono kiseki no ito
in so many miraculous threads
tsunagatte karamatte tadoritsuita yo
it all starts here and now
hajimeru no wa ima kono basho kara
it'll clear up after the rain, become that cloud
ame nochi hare ano kumo ni nare
and swim towards the present
ima wo oyoi de yuku
toss away the hesitation
sono kokoro shibaritsuketeru
that clings to your heart
tamerai furihodoite
you and I held hands
kimi to boku nigirishimeta
and deep inside
futatsu no te no naka de
is the eternal proof of you
kieru koto nai kimi no akashi
with our liberated hands
jiyuu na sono ryoute de
let's start again, from here
koko kara mata hajimeyou
Next Episode
I'll show them why I'm the one guarding the coastline.
I'll launch the opening shot, then you all engage! Continue!
I won't let you pass!
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
You didn't need to get up.
美空ひばりです。
Who's the one who lifted me up?
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "Battleground!"
Battleground!
I'm going to retrieve here, what I previously forsook!
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の豪華な
歌手の皆さんによる→
Tune in again!